Ibrahim Mnaimne

Ibrahim.mneimneh3@gmail.com ❖ +90(541) 102-3436 ❖ location: Istanbul, Turkey

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/ibrahim-mnaimne-160ab4254/
- https://github.com/ibrahimmn

EDUCATION

Istanbul Aydin University

06/2023

Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering

Istanbul, Turkey

■ 3.23/4.0 GPA

SUMMARY

Entry-level Front end developer, full stack developer and computer engineer, with almost 1 year work experience seeking a challenging position to utilize my technical expertise and creative problem-solving abilities in developing user-friendly and visually appealing web applications with strong and clean back end.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hubinit 11/2022 - 02/2023

UX/UI and Front end developer Intern

Amsterdam, Netherlands

- Collaborated with a team of developers to design and implement user interfaces for web applications.
- Developed responsive web pages using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, WordPress elementor and Figma, and JavaScript, ensuring compatibility across multiple browsers and devices.
- Integrated front-end components with back-end systems, working closely with the development team to achieve seamless functionality.
- Finished developing companies' website in 1 week.
- Conducted thorough testing and debugging to identify and resolve issues, optimizing the performance and user experience of the applications.
- Actively participated in Agile sprints, providing regular updates on progress and contributing to sprint planning and retrospectives.

HediyeSepeti 10/2020 - 02/2021

Back end Developer Intern

Istanbul, Turkey

- Developed and maintained web applications using PHP, MySQL, and Laravel framework.
- Designed and implemented efficient database structures and optimized queries to ensure optimal performance and data integrity.
- Implemented RESTful APIs to facilitate data exchange between the front-end and back-end systems, ensuring seamless communication.
- Worked with version control systems (e.g., Git) to track and manage code changes, facilitating collaborative development.

Appen 04/2023 - Present

Data Collector Remote

- Working on project crescent, labeling data, tagging videos and images, and reviewing search engine results.
- Coordinated, scheduled and executed in-depth data entry projects.

CERTIFICATIONS, SKILLS, INTERESTS & LANGUAGES

Certifications:

- o Front End Development Libraries freeCodeCamp. Certificate
- o React.js Code Challenges LinkedIn. Certificate
- o React.js Essential Training LinkedIn. Certificate
- React: Creating and Hosting a Full-Stack Site LinkedIn. <u>Certificate</u>

Skills:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- Redux
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind
- SASS
- jQuery
- React
- React native
- PHP
- Laravel
- Node.js (Express.js)
- Axios
- Auth0 and Firebase
- RESTful APIs
- Responsive web design
- Web development
- Search engine optimization (SEO)
- Git and Agile methodologies
- UI/UX design and Figma
- Object-oriented programming and Java
- Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Google cloud
- WordPress
- SQL, mySQL and MongodB
- Networking, AI, embedded systems, cyber security, and information systems security.

Soft skills:

- Problem-solving and debugging skills.
- Effective communication.
- Collaborative.
- Detail-oriented and committed to delivering high-quality code with consistency.
- Eager to learn.
- Passionate.
- Strong time management skills, and consistent, handling multiple projects simultaneously and meeting deadlines.
- Flexible
- Interests: Body building; swimming; video games; Anime.

Languages:

- o Arabic: Native
- o English: Full professional proficiency
- o French: Intermediate